Ruoqi Tian

8352 Lincoln Ave ♦ Evansville, IN 47715 ♦ 812-618-7548 ♦ trq411@gmail.com http://ruoqitian.com

OBJECTIVE

Obtain full-time employment as a software engineer

SUMMARY

Over three years of programming experience; Campus leader with proven skills in leading; Record of personal and academic achievement; Works wells in teams and individually; Good communication skills

Programming Skills

Perl Ruby on Rails Python SOAP Oracle SQL Java Javascript C/C++ HTML/CSS Git/Subversion

EDUCATION

B.S. in Computer Science; Minor in Mathematics
UNIVERSITY OF EVANSVILLE Evansville, IN

Dean's List Four Terms

GPA 3.46

WORK EXPERIENCE

METRONET INC Evansville, IN

Software Engineer

May 2017-Present

- Designed and implemented multiple web applications on both front and back ends. Utilizing front end design, SOAP web services, Perl modules, and Oracle databases
- Retrieved and manipulated information from SQL databases containing millions of subscriber records
- Created automated recurring Perl scripts to provide scheduled emails and reports

METRONET INC Evansville, IN

MIS Intern

May 2016-April 2017

- Developed JavaScript files, Perl modules, and XML web services for web applications
- Wrote Oracle SQL queries to access important customer data from a large network of databases

UNIVERSITY OF EVANSVILLE Evansville, IN

Supplemental Instruction Leader (C and C++)

Spring 2016

Helped CS students with projects and homework and fielded all questions about project design

Projects

- Collaborated with a large corporation to design and implement Field Tech Admin, a web tool capable of solving critical problems and providing great efficiency to field workers; utilized Perl, SQL, and SOAP; Expanded knowledge of web server structures and Foundation
- Independently developed an Instagram-style web application using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL where users can upload sky-related photographs; deployed on Amazon Web Services
- Worked within a team of two and developed a Python based web application that generated electronic coupons for grocery stores to sell online and automatically charged users through PayPal API
- Independently coded the website for a local coffee corporation emphasizing proficiency in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Foundation 6, and JQuery

CAMPUS LEADERSHIP

ASSOCIATION FOR COMPUTING MACHINERY (ACM), UE Student Chapter

Chapter Treasurer/Secretary

March 2015-May 2017

• Facilitated monthly chapter meetings for a group of 10 demonstrating effective leadership and interpersonal communication skills

International Orientation Leader

March 2014-May 2017

• Mentored and introduced international students to the American campus life and cultures